what delivery method for estrogen
progesterone and testosterone would you
suggest is best to start out on for the
first time after a full and complete
hysterctomy right well I mean there's a
lot of options and they all work and it
really depends on if you are going you
know the commercial route or the
compounded route but of course I'm very
partial to the wonderful compounding
pharmacy that we use uh crestf City and
they make us these rapid dissolve tabs
that are sublingual and what I what I
love about it is first of all they're
totally customizable right and you can
also get all of your hormones replaced
with two tablets so we give you a
morning tab that contains pregnanolone
DHEA and testosterone so you get the two
precursors and the testosterone and then
we give you another tablet at bedtime
with estriol estradiol and progesterone
and of course we give that to you at
bedtime because the progesterone helps
you sleep and so I like that we can do
the full complement of of all the
hormones that you need in two easy
sublingual tabs and like I said the
doses of everything are are fully
customizable so I'm I'm definitely
biased so I think that's a good place to
start I will say with the
testosterone it's been my experience so
if you have never been on testosterone
before the tablets are great and again
I'm not against I'm not against creams
or patches I'm not against any of it um
if you are not new to testosterone
though I have a lot of patients that
come to me uh with a history of pellet
therapy and if you have ever been on
pellets or injectable testosterone then
I always go straight to injectable
testosterone because when someone has
been on like a stronger form the tablets
are just not not enough and I give
people the tablets and they just say
they don't feel anything it doesn't work
and so if if they have a history like
because I get a lot of patients that
previously were on pellets and they want
to transition off the pellets and then I
then I go straight to
injectable yeah very interesting yeah
and what I like about the injectable
over the pellets is that with the
pellets you know again I'm not anti-
pellet right like a lot of people take
them and they feel great and it's
wonderful but the thing with the pellets
is you put it in and there it is and if
the dose is not quite right there's
really nothing you can do besides just
wait it out right and what's nice about
the injectable is that you have the
bottle you have the needles and so you
can uh figure out how much you need to
take every week and so if you do a dose
and it turns out that it's it's too high
so you just do a little less next week
like it's you know it's not like you're
overdose for months on end you know just
a couple days and you know and it it's
out of your system and and you know if
it's not enough again you can increase
the dose for the following week like
it's just a lot easier to manipulate so
I I like the injectable a lot yeah sure
it's easier to
control